FAIZAN SAJID

Front-end Engineer

Transforming imagination into reality

LinkedIn www.linkedin.com/faizan-sajid

GitHub www.github.com/faizan-sajid

Portfolio portfolio-faizan

Email fsajid68@gmail.com

Contact 6378587224

OBJECTIVE

Passionate front-end engineer with technical expertise from the School of Accelerated Learning. Dedicated to transforming imagination into reality by creating user-friendly digital experiences. Driven to build awesome websites and apps, I enthusiastically embrace challenges and aim to contribute meaningfully to the evolving world of digital development.

EXPERIENCE

March 2024 - Present

Frontend developer in Synilogic tech private limited.

- Developed responsive user interfaces using React.js, HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Crafting app mockups and prototypes in Figma, collaborating with other designers to create visually engaging and user-friendly web applications & mobile apps.
- Collaborating with teams to refine ideas, focusing on the user experience to make sure the final product is not only functional but also enjoyable to use.

June 2021 - Aug 2022

Shift in charge in Svaar process solution pvt ltd.

Proficiently managed equipment and evaporation process.

[Dec 2020 - May 2021]

DET - Diploma engineer trainee in Ansun multitech ltd.

• Operated and maintained electroplating process and equipment, including tank management.

PROJECTS

Astrology Kundli - Website.

- Spearheaded the design and smooth implementation of the entire frontend architecture for displaying Kundli and other astrologyrelated information.
- Integrated API Services to fetch astrological data and Built PDF Generation Functionality.

Technologies: React js, Css, Redux toolkit

<u>Ai Astrology – Website</u>

• Developed a responsive website frontend that provides AI-powered astrology predictions.

Technologies: Html, CSS, Java script, bootstrap, Aos

Visit at: aiastro

EDUCATION

School of accelerated learning:

Product Engineer Certificate – 2023 Present

Yogiraj institute of technology:

Diploma in chemical engineering Percentage: 74% - Nov 2020

TECHNICAL SKILLS

☐ React Native
☐ React.js
☐ Electron.js
☐ Redux Toolkit
☐ Javascript
□ Css

SOFT SKILLS

☐ Html

	Team Captain
	Team Player
	Client Care Specialis
	Adaptability and Flexibility
	Researching
	Project Management

☐ Problem Solving

TOOLS

OLS	
	Vs Cod
	GitHub
	Figma
	Filmora